to see another way of initial access
to be using the scanning tools for you are no
if you want to know about your enemy you need to gather some information about the about
you enemy right that the same way if you're targeting one organization you need to know about the organization what service of their are using
version of the service service and whether they are using any victims like easily targeted
services like VPNs are 3 3 8 and so in this video we are going to see another one of
a day the threat types will be used most of that in the same the ransomware so we are facing
40 to 50% of the attacks from the RDP sessions okay so let's start our video in the practical
let me I'm putting the 3 3 8 9 so if you know about the 3 3 8 9 port that belongs to
an RDP okay so the port 21 belongs to the FTP port 3 3 8 9 belongs to an RDP okay so let's
open any of the terminal so if you see here R 3 3 8 9 there's a remote RDP connection has been
available right so we can connect through the RDP so it was in the public facing application
so we can use this RDP connection to get into a machine okay so that's the point so in this
IP here you can find there's a RDP has been open and here the RDP has been open and
okay so let's get on to the practical so I just created a I just installed one of the
VM and I'm going to hack this VM using the RDP methods okay so first of all V need if we need
to if we need to log into the RDP we need the user name sent password okay so we will be
get clear about this video let me will do on by one okay so I just created one of the user
called my username is AJ away and my password will be passed this is my username and password again let's
I will just typing here blindly let me go to the user ij yeah so my password will dts okay so I'm
logged into my user username okay so let's go to an exploit okay so for RDP brute forcing I'm
going to use a hydra okay so here is a hydra command I'm going to use a hydra for the RDP
brute force okay so the T will be let me explain the hydra command hydra dash fetch so if the
first option will be T right so if you go for a T it's a task okay so we are going to target
a only one target okay we are going to target a Windows machine so it's a only one target so the
next one so the next command will be one we are going to target one okay right Cv will be a verbose
verbose will be giving more additional information that's all and Fpld let's see that yeah
so when a username password is successfully found we need to terminate decisions right so we will be
will be seeing there seeing this later so dash L means a login name and dash T means a password okay
so let me give the login name as ij so this is the test dot txt I just created one that was filed
sorry one of the text to dogman like let me give some more thing there's the file we are going to
use for a brute force okay so the threat actors contain lot and lot of passwords in the file I will
be I will be getting you how to take this password from the GitHub so here you can find I have
created a small word list for doing a brute force so let me do a brute force okay so let me do
a brute force and we will be we'll go for a login okay so let me so now the attack has been
started so you can find so it was attacking one by one the username is a j it was trying one by
one basically the brute force means means like a trying one by one uh username sent password okay
so we have created a few passwords in the uh file test dot txt and we are we are going to try
one by one one by one username and password okay so you can see it first you tried a j a the first
entry so the login was failed okay zero child so the login was failed and you tried the next entry
next line so next the line was failed and it tried one by one one and finally if you see the last
so I can get a green line for a j so RDB goes to be the username and password will be passed okay
so we are successfully found the RDP section in the same way in the same way the threat actors
will be using this okay in the same way the threat actors will be using this
uh publicly available available RDP service uh for a brute force okay they will be
they will be brute they will be brute forcing this kind of publicly accessible service
and they will be finding their username sent passwords and they will be logging into their
machine so I will be giving so how to login into I will be giving a small example how to
login into the machine so already we have found a username and password this is the one I just
created for my own okay so I will be getting you how to take a big brute force like documents
like login fields like username sent password so x3 RDP there is a one tool called xp RDP for
Linux machine so you can go for a user user a j a y and you can go for a password so password we
know we already brute force p a s s will be the password and we need to do the uh
host name okay so host name on an IP address so my host name will be our IP address will be
the 192.160.18.10 so this is this is 10 windows machine so this is the windows machine host name
which I create um install okay so let's 192.168.18.10 so let me enter so now it's now it was asking
some certification let me UI so now you can see I got a clean connect directly right I got a
screen correct I can able to control each and everything okay I can able to do anything here okay
so I can go to the browser uh okay so this section will be logged out okay so I can go to the
browser I can do whatever I want I can do okay I can do anything okay so this is the way the thread
factors will brute force the RDP use an event password they will be using this kind of uh X3 RDP
or any other tools they will be logging into their machine directly okay so this is a very very
powerful method the thread tactics will be followed you can do anything you can go to anywhere you
can go to uh any you can set anything you want okay so this is the uh another way exploiting the
remote services so this you need to be very very careful so if you are username and passwords are
very weak if your password was weak okay the thread tactics can able to easily uh enter into our
organization okay so uh so you can see how easy I get into the getting to the server right I just
created a small um group a small uh word list for a brute force attempt for my brute force
and I use the hydro tool for a brute force finally I got a username and password I use the
username and password I use a name and password for login into the login to the RDP right so it's a
very very uh EC method and it's a very powerful method the thread tactics will be following I will
be given I will be giving a live example so how the thread tactics will be using the RDP so how we
did the same with the the tactics will be using the hackers will be using so RDP so you can see RDP
can be used by a ransomware attack typically the port 3 3 8 9 we already queried with the
sold on 3 3 8 9 so you can find everything here 3 3 8 9 remote desktop protocol okay so you
can uh do some brute forcing in that and you can get the current shells and you can directly log
into the organization this is the uh one of the way okay so here you can find a lot and lot of
ransomware they will be using uh so see here RDP abuse prevents in 90 percent of the ransomware
breaches okay so 90 percent of the ransomware uh breaches it will be happened by the RDP so if you see
this thread scalar ball RDP uh so ransomware delivery delivered using RDP brute force attempt okay
so how we did the brute forcing the similar way the same way the threat tactics will be
doing the brute force attempt they will be get inside the machine okay so you will need to be
very careful uh about that okay so the threat tactics will be using RDP for a initial access okay
so let's uh I hope you have clear understanding about the RDP so first of all we uh just created
one of the word list file uh to use for a brute force and we use a hydro tool to brute force the
RDP and finally we got a username and passwords so next we use the x3 RDP to log it into the
username and uh login into the our Windows machine right so next we use the username and password
to login into the Windows machine right so this is the same way so you'll be using you'll be
exploiting the RDP in the public facing applications okay and uh instead of this IP you will be
giving a uh your target your company which company you are targeting that IP okay so I hope you
have a clear understanding about this video how the threat tactics will be uh hijacking uh
our brute forcing RDP and get into the access we will uh I will get into one more thing
there will be a brute force passwords and all draw q dot txt uh 2024
so here is a bird list so this bird list contained a lot and a lot of passwords okay so you can
see here it's a 133 mb uh you will be getting 133 megabytes of passwords megabytes of passwords
probably more than uh more than like uh blacks and lacs of passwords so we'll be getting
early you are using this file for a for a brute force okay so instead of giving the
test to dot txt you can give the rachu dot txt okay very really okay opening
okay so here you can find a lot of username and password here so there's um it's uncountable okay
many many usernames and password okay so instead of you can using the just test to file
I'll be using the rachu dot txt so if I need to brute force this kind of public facing
applications okay so be very careful the threat tactics will be using RDP for initial access
so your username and passwords will be very strong um so if your if your service RDP service is
publicly accessible okay so your RDP username and password will be very strong if you're using the
RDP in a publicly accessible next thing so if you don't want RDP for publicly accessible
you need to restrict that protocol you need to block that port okay uh so preventing this kind
of attack if there is no RDP in their uh company environment so the threat tactics can't able to
attack the RDP they can't able to brute force the RDP they can't able to get into set
get inside the organization through the RDP okay so the first recommendation to the so use a
very good uh passwords so that will be um unknown by uh threat tactics and the next one
so restrict the RDP and the final recommendation uh if you have if you can able to enable the
multi-factor authentication like your two way authentication like uh by uh by uh authenticating through
the mobile uh so some more DPP will be sent into the mobile like that so go for that okay these are
the recommendations you need to provide to the customers okay so i hope you have a clear understanding
about the RDP control so how we how we got the got have you got the RDP so i can able to control
each and everything uh in this machine okay so let's pop off this video and we will continue our
discussion in the next video see you guys bye bye if you have any questions any queries just uh
bring in a comment